《女子监狱》
第二季第九集
查普曼办理手续  查普曼办理手续
Chapman to processing. Chapman to processing.
我知道我说了要烤的  斯科特
I know I said toasted, Scott.
但如果你在上面盖张纸巾的话
If you cover it with a paper towel,
等我检查完蛀牙  它就还是热的
it'll still be warm when I finish the cavity search.
坐N号线  谢谢
Take the n train. Thank you.
走吧
Off you go.
咳一下
Cough.
你可以用力点  撑开你的粉菊花
You can do better than that. Shake out that pink.
我难道会想把监狱里的东西带出去吗
What could I possibly be trying to take out of prison?
这是规矩  别问道理  站起来
It's procedure. Don't look for logic. Stand up.
换上这些衣服
Change into these.
赶紧的  有些人还想吃百吉饼呢
Hurry up. Some of us have bagels to eat.
你是否了解等你回来后
Do you understand you will be subjected to
需要接受尿检并且上述检查的费用
a urinalysis upon your return and said test
需由你自己承担
is your own financial responsibility?
我明白
Yes.
你不可以购买  销售  拥有  使用
You may not purchase, sell, possess, use,
消费或给予任何毒品  大麻  酒精
consume, or administer any narcotic drugs, marijuana, alcohol,
或任何形式的麻醉品
or intoxicants of any form
也不得前往非法出售  分发
or frequent places where such articles are
使用或赠送以上物品的地点
unlawfully sold, dispensed, used, or given away.
-你说的真溜  -多谢夸奖
-That was really impressive. - Thanks.
我在脑子里搭着《扑克脸》的调说的  便于记忆
I sing it to the tune of poker face in my head to remember.
嘎嘎小姐唱的  你想听吗
Lady gaga? You wanna hear?
不用了  没关系
No, that... That's okay.
走吧  小鸟  自由的飞翔吧
Go ahead, little bird. Fly free.
帕波
Pipette!
那是接你的车吗
Is that your ride?
我以为你是雅皮士而不是嬉皮士
Pegged you more for a yuppie than a hippie.
所有来访者必须向警官报告
犯人  48小时后见
See you in 48 hours, inmate.
快到绿色机器里来
Come inside the green machine!
-怎么了  -为什么闻起来像天妇罗
- What? - Why does it smell like tempura?
没错  植物油  慢慢熟悉吧
Oh, yeah, vegetable oil. Get hip to it.
是内莉跟我们家前面那家铁板烧店换来的
Neri barters with this teppanyaki place up the road from us.
友希很喜欢内莉仙女外套
Yuki loves neri's fairy coats.
怎么了
What's up?
难以相信她死了
Just can't believe she's dead.
了解  了解
I know. I know.
如果能让你感觉好点的话
If it makes you feel any better,
你并没有错过太多
you didn't miss much.
她就是睡了几天
She just slept for a few days,
然后就永远地睡了过去
and then the sleep stopped being temporary.
我都没机会跟她道别
I didn't get a chance to say goodbye.
我替你说了
I told her for you.
她知道的  帕波
She knew, Piper.
准备走了吗  请系好安全带
Ready? Seat belts, please.
下一个
Next.
三瓶达什太太牌的调味粉
Three Mrs. Dash's table blend,
四瓶柠檬汁  五瓶阿斗波粉
four lemon juices, five adobo powders,
外加两瓶洋葱粉
and two onion powders.
哇  山雀大妈
Whoo-wee, chickadee.
你现在还要用这些调料做什么
What do you need with all these spices these days?
这可不管你的事
Oh, that's none of your business.
你肯定有很多私房钱  是吧
You must have a pretty hefty fund, huh?
你那些没用的儿子终于洗心革面了吗
Those no-good sons finally doing the right thing?
达米特里是不是中彩票大奖了
Dmitri hit it big with a scratcher ticket?
不要谈论我的家人
Don't you dare talk about my family.
虽然现在经济形势不太好
Maybe your little market turned around
不过可能你的小店生意好转了吧
in spite of the economy and everything.
犯人  请保持队伍前进
Let's keep the line moving, inmates.
-调料给我  -好
- The spices, please. - All righty.
很高兴看到你找到了自己的生活方式
It just warms my heart to see you finding your way in here,
和一群老年人共同生活
settling in with the aarp crowd.
园艺似乎是个挺舒服的活
Gardening looks like a comfortable little life.
下一个
Next.
妮琪  妮琪
Nicky. Nicky!
我需要你帮忙
I need a favor.
那得看你能出多少
Well, that's gonna cost you.
你要什么
What's your price?
燕麦馅饼
Oatmeal pies.
那小东西虽然
The little debbie ones that
会让你沾上满手油渍
leave that oily residue all over your hands,
但还是非常美味
but are still somehow delicious.
成交
Done.
我要你明天带所有姑娘们去温室房
I need you to bring all the girls to the greenhouse tomorrow...
在晚餐的时候
At dinnertime.
那你得给我两盒
That'll run you two boxes.
如果你想听我的意见  你这方法完全不对
And if you want my opinion, you're going about this all wrong.
这一次会非常特别的
This is going to be really special.
你即使在难吃的蛋糕上面加一层糖衣
You know, another layer of icing on a shit cake
也不会让它变得好吃
doesn't make it taste good.
我听不懂你在说什么
I don't understand what you...
你知道你还有什么话没说吗  红妈
Well, you know what you haven't said, Red?
498号  干扰警务人员执行公务
498! Interfering with a staff member in performance of duties.
难道你的男朋友没教你
Didn't your boyfriend teach you
要怎么对待警官的吗  下垂妹
how to treat a staff member, Floppy Tits?
一次警告
That's a shot!
母猪  你衬衫上是什么东西
Hey! What's on your shirt there, Pigpen?
是屎  眼泪还是薯片
Shit? Tears? Potato chips?
330号  不卫生
330! Being unsanitary.
记过  我不喜欢你的表情
Shot! I don't like your face.
312号  傲慢  记过
312. Insolence. Shot!
贱人们  我门德斯回来了
Mendez is back, bitches.
他来这里干什么
What the hell is he doing here?
约翰  这真是个美好的早晨
Why, yes, John, it's a beautiful morning.
甚至很平静
Peaceful, even.
先生您知道的  他危及到犯人们的安全
He endangers the inmates, and you know it, sir.
他出现在这里甚至是不合法的  是吧
I mean, it can't even be legal to have him here, can it?
-你要不要先坐下来  -不用
- Would you like to have a seat? - No.
他的停职结束了  所以我们必须得面对
His suspension is up, so we're gonna have to deal with it.
还有  只跟你说
And between you and me,
管理层有人觉得我们需要人手
some of the administration feel there's a job to do.
没有别人能胜任这个位置
No one else is up to the task.
我能够
I'm up to the task.
很好  证明一下
Good. Prove it.
我会的
I will.
何不说说来这的原因   用你自己的话说
Why don't we start with why you're here. In your opinion.
有不只一个人
Well, it was... suggested to me...
建议我要来看看
by more than one person.
那么马泽尔博士
So... Uh, Dr. Maser...
叫我克莉丝就好  我不是博士
Oh, just "Chris," Please. I'm not a doctor.
或许这不是个好主意
Maybe this was a bad idea.
山姆  感觉不爽没有关系
Well, it's okay to be uncomfortable, Sam.
我会鼓励你接受这种感觉
It's a feeling I would encourage you to embrace.
接受它吗  我都活在这感觉中
Embrace it? I live it.
我对整个生活都感到不爽
My whole life is uncomfortable.
所有这些女人  罪犯  白痴般的官僚们
All these women, criminals, bureaucratic idiots.
我在自己家甚至都没有家的感觉
I don't even feel at home in my own home anymore.
现在我在一间墙上挂着
And now I'm sitting in an office
古怪青蛙油画的办公室里坐着
with some weird painting of frogs,
而这些画我猜本应该是舒缓心情的
which I'm guessing is supposed to be soothing.
山姆  我觉得你的压力很大
Sam, I'm hearing a lot of stress.
没错  大到甚至都无法形容
Yeah, well, that doesn't even begin to cover it, okay?
你喜欢你的工作吗
Do you like your job?
以前喜欢过  真的
I used to. I really did.
我觉得自己很能干
I felt useful.
是什么改变了
And what changed?
我知道就见鬼了
Hell if I know.
我变老了
I got older.
或许我在乎的更少了
Maybe I care less.
或许看得多了  知道我没办法改变现状
Maybe I've seen enough to know that I won't make a difference.
知道这是在浪费时间
That it's all a waste.
你知道
You know...
有时候我们总从一个角度看问题  会困住
sometimes we get stuck seeing things from one perspective,
但如果我们能稍微改变看问题的角度
but if we can just shift our perspective even a little bit,
一切就会大不相同
makes all the difference.
就这样吗
That's it?
这就是你高达75美元一小时的建议吗
That's your fancy, $75-an-hour advice?
你对我的收费感到不爽吗
Are you uncomfortable with the amount I charge?
我以为我们刚刚已经说明
I thought we just established
我对一切都感到不爽
that I'm uncomfortable with everything!
你一直是这样易怒吗
Are you always this quick to anger?
你一直是这样高人一等的贱人吗
Are you always a condescending cunt?
抱歉  我真的抱歉
Oh, I'm sorry. I'm really sorry.
我想我们的工作不好做啊
Well, I think we have our work cut out for us.
我的鞋子有点紧
My shoes feel tight.
我要说的是这个人叫海因里希・德莱塞
But I'm saying this guy, Heinrich Dreser,
他应该被直接归到坏人那一类
deserves to be right up there on the bad-guy shelf.
我们的伙计海因里希
So, our buddy Heinrich
拜耳  德国著名药企
在拜耳负责管理海洛因的药物开发
oversaw the development of heroin at Bayer.
拜耳公司在1900年代初期将这种药物
Yep. So, the corporate suits at Bayer sold this shit over the counter
作为非成瘾性的吗啡替代品放到柜台出售
as a non-addictive morphine substitute in the early 1900s,
你知道为什么他们称它为海洛因吗
and you know why they called it heroin?
因为当他们开始测试这药物的时候
'Cause when they started testing it,
人们说这药会让他们感觉很英勇
people said it made them feel heroic. Right?
我想站在这里作为恢复好的人  鼓励大家
I'd like to stand up here and be all inspiring and recovered
告诉你们我戒掉了
and tell you I'm over it,
不过我每天还是非常想念
but I miss it every fucking day, you know?
海洛因是我一生的爱
Uh, heroin is the love of my life,
她是我的最佳女友
she's my best girlfriend...
她是我的灵魂伴侣
she's my soul mate,
因为没有东西比她能让我感觉更好受
'cause, you know, she makes me feel better than anything.
最后我要说一句
So, in closing, uh...
操他妈的德国人
fuck the Germans.
好了  今天就讲这些  孩子们
Okay, that's it for today, kids.
努力接受你所不能改变的现实
Strength to accept what you cannot change,
神奇仙尘  独角兽之类的
magical fairy dust, unicorns, etcetera.
你是罗莎对吧
Hey. Rosa, right?
多谢你还记得我的名字
How kind of you to remember.
你读过这本书吗  关于患癌儿童的
Did you read this? It's about kids with cancer.
我不知道为什么这个傻逼作者想写这样的书
I don't know why the sick fuck wanted to write about this.
总之我想你会对这本书感兴趣
Anyway, I... I thought it might be right up your alley.
我的人生已经足够压抑了
I got enough depressing shit in my life.
我不想读的书也那么压抑
I don't need it in my books, too.
那么你的逃避方式是什么
So, what's your escape, then, huh?
是吃止疼片  还是喝酒
Is it pain pills, booze?
每个人时不时都需要帮助应对现实
Everybody needs a little bit of help with reality now and then.
关于现实那件事
The thing about reality...
就是它明天早上依然会等着你
is it's still there waiting for you the next morning.
不错的演讲  辩论队肯定会喜欢你
Nice talk. They must've loved you on the debate team.
是啊
Oh, yeah.
我曾连续两年在原创辩论赛中拿第一
I was first place Original Oratory two years running.
直到我弄伤了教练的脚趾被开除
You know, until I got expelled for breaking my coach's toe.
一言难尽  现在说不清楚
Long story, not for now.
可以找一天聊聊
Maybe one day.
好的  当然
Uh, yeah, sure.
我来这是帮你减轻负担的
I am here to unburden you.
拿到我的东西了没
You got my goods?
你已经拿到大部分了
You got most of them already.
虽然我俄语说的不溜  但在西语和英语中
Ooh, I'm not fluent in Russian, but in Spanish and English,
"大部分"就意味着不是全部
"Most of them" Means not all of them.
歌洛丽娅  你了解我的
Gloria, you know me.
其余的很快就到
The rest will be here soon.
我是一个言出必行的女人
I'm a woman of my word.
而我是一个要求按时交货的女人
And I'm a woman who gets paid on time in full.
瑞泽尼科夫  你越界了
Reznikov, you're out of bounds.
你叫我什么来着
What did you call me?
马上回到界内来
Get back in bounds right now.
你什么时候开始关心我站哪了
Since when do you care where I am?
记过一次
That's a shot.
307号  拒绝服从警务人员的命令
307, refusing to obey an order from a staff member.
他现在是你的走狗吗
He's your bulldog now?
不是  别看我
Oh, no. Don't look at me.
他没链子拴着  我也不想被他咬
He's off leash, and I don't want to get bitten, either.
回见
I'll see you around.
别让我再抓到你在厨房边上
Don't let me catch you anywhere near the kitchen again.
你知道该怎么做
You know the drill.
你会是个了不起的父亲
You're going to make a great father.
你还好吗  亲爱的
You okay, hon?
我很好  谢谢
Fine, yes. Thank you.
这需要适应  他们是这么说的
It's an adjustment. That's what they say.
你的生活费到了吗
Your commissary come through yet?
-没有  -没有吗  我也是
- No. - No? Me, either.
我昨天进来后就没刷过牙
Haven't brushed my teeth since we came in yesterday.
我开始感觉像是穿了一件兔毛衫
Starting to feel like an angora sweater in there.
这里有个叫卡拉的女人  她会帮你整理
There's this lady in here, Carla, she'll wanna do that for you.
我以前来过  我能行
I've been around before. I got it.
我要去洗手间
I gotta take a leak.
你是帕克吗  我是朗达
You Parker? Rhonda.
给你带了一些东西  算是见面礼
Brought you some stuff, a little welcome basket.
我们早餐时见
We'll see you at breakfast.
我不吃早饭
I don't eat breakfast.
早饭会让我肠胃不适
It upsets my stomach.
现在你要吃了
You eat it now.
我们走
Let's go.
想要点吗
Want some of this?
不用了  谢谢
No, thank you.
里面有三支牙刷  她们只是在炫耀
Three toothbrushes in here. It's just showing off.
给你  拿一支吧
Here. Take one, please.
谢谢
Thank you.
牙膏也给你
Get some toothpaste, too.
你真好
You're very kind.
你有分配到工作吗
You got assigned a work detail yet?
厨房
Kitchen.
那是个好工作
That's a plum gig.
是的  就像在家一样
Yes, feels like home.
我家里开了一家小店  我负责做吃的
My family, we own a small market, and I serve food there.
是吗  你是个好厨师吗
Yeah? You a good cook?
我很会做菜  还有听着
I am very good. And get this.
我用的原料跟这里的厨房用的一样
I use the same produce people that the kitchen here uses.
不过如果他们当初敢给我这里拿到的那种破烂货
Although, if they delivered me the shit they send here,
我会把东西扔回他们脸上
I would throw it in their faces.
他们知道要给我好东西
They knew to give me the good stuff.
他们欠我的
They owed me.
现在他们真的欠我了
Now they really owe me.
海王星  真是愚蠢的名字
Neptune. Stupid name.
我告诉过他们海王星应该卖海鲜而不是水果
I told them Neptune is for seafood, not fruit.
你认识供应商吗
You know a vendor?
不只是认识  他们是因为我来这的
Know them? They're here because of me.
而我进这里也是因为他们
And I'm here because of them.
你得利用这点  让你的监狱生活好过些
You need to use that. Make your life here better.
就是因为犯法才让我进了监狱
Breaking rules got me in here.
没错  我不是要对你指手画脚
Yeah, well, I'm not telling you what to do, you know.
我只是在告诉你如何生存
I'm just telling you how to survive.
下一个
Next.
只要一支  我刚发现
Only one. I just learned I like a smoke
我读完中篇小说后  喜欢抽上一支
after I read my sexy-time novellas.
感觉棒极了  但
It feels glamorous, but like,
我仍然不是一个真正的烟客
I'm still not a real smoker, you know?
没错  好了
Yeah, all right.
请确保将这本书重新放到合适的书架
Just make sure you reshelve this book in its proper place.
我们这里是按照杜威狗屁分类法摆放的
We on Dewey decimal and shit in here.
别让我在超自然现象区找到水上运动的书
Don't let me find no aquatic sports over in paranormal phenomena.
-明白  -好
- Got it. - All right.
操
Fuck you.
多谢了  真是量多的一天
Oh, thanks, man. Heavy flow day over here.
我把你手弄伤了吗
I break your hand?
快回去干活
Get back to your job.
我按了门铃  是不是很奇怪
Hi, I rang the bell. Is that weird?
我不想直接走进来
I didn't wanna just walk right in.
没关系  不用这样
It... It's fine. You're fine. Wow, it's...
你真的回来了  太疯狂了
You're actually here. It's crazy.
是啊
Yeah.
不许接触
No touching!
抱歉  我只是想让你的过渡平稳些
Sorry. I'm just trying to ease your transition.
变化太多太快对你不宜
Too much, too fast can be a shock to the system.
就像战俘们终于有东西吃的时候
Like when POWs finally get to eat,
他们会吃太多导致把胃撑破
and then they eat too much and their stomachs explode?
-不过我们俩可以接触  -是的  你好
- We can touch, though. - Yeah, hello.
你好  很高兴见到你
Hello, good to see you.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
直到离开一段时间之后
You never remember what home smells like
你才会记得家里的味道
until you've been gone for a while.
我记得以前总会
I remember that I always used
在从露营回来时有这种感觉
to think about that when I got back from camp,
身上都是我朋友的味道
that I was smelling what my friends smelled.
是什么味道
What's it like?
你的味道
You.
洗衣粉的味道
Laundry detergent. That, um...
那些在安托保罗杰店里买的蜡烛的味道
Those candles from Anthropologie.
安托保罗杰
一家以人类学的法语名称命名的美国零售商
还有咖啡的味道
And... coffee.
咖啡  来点咖啡吧
Coffee? Coffee?
好的
Sure.
这些都是我的东西吗
Hey, is this all... is this all my stuff?
是的
It's your stuff.
我怎么会有那么多衣服  天呐
Why do I have so many clothes? My God.
我真的觉得需要所有这些东西吗
Did I really think that I needed all of these?
天啊  我的羊绒衫
Oh, my God. Oh, my God, my cashmere sweater!
莱瑞  我的裤子装在哪袋
Larry, which one has all my pants in it?
那些可能已经在波丽家了
Those are probably over at Polly's already.
她怎么样
Oh, how is she?
-波丽吗  -是的
- Polly? Um... - Yeah.
她很好  我想她过的挺好
She's fine. She's fine, I think. You know?
她明天可能来不了
She's probably not gonna make it tomorrow.
她正在给孩子做睡眠训练
She's sleep training the baby and...
她说这个训练真的很辛苦
she said it's been... It's been really tough on her, so...
我对塞莱斯特的去世真的很遗憾
Hey, I'm sorry about... sorry about Celeste.
多谢了  布鲁姆
Thanks, Bloomer.
没事
Oh, it's fine.
不  感觉不好
No, it's not fine.
不好  你记得妈妈的那个枕头吗
It's not. Do you remember that pillow that Mom had?
枕头背后有一只奶牛
The one with the cow on its back
奶牛的腿都朝上的
and its legs were all up in the air?
在奶牛下面写着  "我很好  真的"
Uh, under the cow it says, "I'm fine, really."
多么傻逼的枕头
What a stupid fuckin' pillow.
现在我在用这个枕头
Oh, I have it now.
味道真不错
That's really good.
沙发座套  这座套真的很舒服
Ooh, upholstery. Upholstery is really good.
如果你想的话可以住在这里
You, uh... you could stay here... if you want.
你这声音听着连逢场作戏都不像
Wow. You couldn't even try to make that sound like you meant it.
不过算你走运
Well, lucky for you,
我的休假令上面要求我要和爸妈一起居住
it's in my furlough paperwork that I have to stay with my parents.
如果你们想的话  我可以在车里等你们
You know, I can wait in the car if you guys would like...
不  你想要什么  莱瑞
No. What do you want, Larry?
我不知道
I don't know.
好吧  瞧见了吧
Okay, see, that's exactly
我就不想把未来两天浪费在这上
how I do not wanna spend these next two days.
如果我不能陪着奶奶
If I can't be with Grandmother,
我至少要为了她好好享受这次旅行
I'm going to at least enjoy this trip for her.
你知道我们要去做什么吗
You know what we're gonna do?
斑点猪餐厅  好吗
The Spotted Pig. Right?
汉堡和黑麦曼哈顿
Burgers and rye Manhattans.
这就是我们要做的事  谁和我一起
That's what we're gonna do. Who's with me?
你不是不应该喝酒吗
Aren't you not supposed to drink?
莱瑞・亚伯拉罕・布鲁姆
Larry Abraham Bloom,
接下来48小时我是自由身
I am free for the next 48 hours.
别像个娘们似的毁了它
Do not ruin this by being a pussy.
求你了
Please.
我能吃东西
I could eat.
瞧见了吗  很好  卡尔你呢
See? Great. Cal?
不错  听起来很好  我喜欢你的想法
Yeah, you know, this sounds great. I like where your head's at.
很高兴知道你的内心仍然
It's great to know that you're still
是一个想违法的罪犯
a rule-breaking criminal at heart.
不过有一件事
But there's this one thing...
感谢你的到来
Thank you for coming.
-很高兴见到你  -非常感谢
- Oh, good to see you, darling. - Thanks so much.
-很高兴见到你  -谢谢
- Nice to see you. - Thanks.
非常感谢你的到来
Thank you so much for coming.
是的  她真的很好
She was great, yes.
不  她没有别的孙女
No, she doesn't have another granddaughter.
真的是我  就是那个重罪犯
That's actually me. The felon.
不  我出来了  但只是暂时的
No, I am out. I'm just not out-out.
这叫做休假
It's called furlough.
是的  暂时的
It's temporary, yeah.
48小时
Forty-eight hours.
很高兴他们能信任我
It... It was nice of them to trust me.
不  瞧见了吗  没有手铐
No, see? No handcuffs.
亲爱的  你还能撑的下去吗
How are you holding up, dear?
你觉得这还要多久
How much longer do you think this is gonna be?
不久  一个小时左右
Not long. An hour or so?
好吧  我还在想或许能
Okay, well, I was thinking that I might...
大家会在7点到房子里
Everyone's coming back to the house at 7:00,
所以我们要在那之前赶到
so we have to be there before then.
葬礼在明天中午  所以早饭要吃好
Funeral's tomorrow at noon, so eat a good breakfast.
大家看到你都很高兴
Everyone's very excited to visit with you.
所以他们都像看动物园的狮子一样盯着我看
So they can all stare at me like a lion in a zoo.
亲爱的  这对大家来说都是困难的一天
Been a difficult day for everyone, dear.
你好  玛丽  感谢你的到来
Hello, Mary. Thank you for coming.
塞莱斯特很鄙视她  她总是穿中跟鞋
Celeste despised her. She always wore kitten heels.
你知道奶奶对中跟鞋的态度
You know how Grandmother felt about them.
鞋子中的奇葩
"The boiled carrots of footwear."
你是把手指插进插座了么
Stick your fingers in a fucking socket?
你头发是怎么回事
What's wrong with your hair?
老天啊  囚犯  你有什么毛病
Jesus Christ. What's wrong with you, inmate?
你是在冥想吗
You meditating?
快去拿点食物  吃点肉长点身子
Get some food. Put some meat on your bones, shit.
我不吃东西
I'm not eating.
我看的见  用我常人的眼睛就能看见
I can see that, by my normal-people eyes.
你眼睛那么小很难看清吧
Bet those slits make it hard for you to see, huh?
我会向管理部门投诉你的
I will report you to the administration.
女士们  囚犯苏苏
Ladies! Inmate... "Soso"?
soso也有马马虎虎之意
你搞笑呢吧
You're shittin' me, right?
囚犯苏苏看来违反了监狱的基本规定
Inmate Soso here seems to be violating essential prison regulations
并且拒不服从指令  对不对
with her insubordinate attitude, does she not?
接招吧  打小报告的
Take that, you tattletale.
我正在发动绝食抗议
I am staging a hunger strike
抗议这个监狱里糟糕的条件
in protest of the reprehensible conditions in this facility!
我邀请大家参与进来  来拥护
I invite you all to join in, in standing up...
212号  参加或怂恿进行团体示威
Oh, 212! Engaging in or encouraging a group demonstration!
苏苏  我们去谈谈你的加班工作吧
Let's go talk about a little extra work duty, shall we, Soso?
大家...请小声点
Just... keep it down, please.
不敢相信你居然把时间浪费在生菜上
Can't believe you're wasting your time on lettuce.
你知道我多久没吃过
Do you know how long it's been since...
能咬的嘎嘣响的蔬菜了吗
I had a vegetable that actually crunched?
喝慢点  饿鬼
Whoa, easy there, Tiger.
真是太美味了
Mmm. But it's so delicious.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
我想念你
Mmm. I missed you.
我也想你  帕波
I missed you, too, Pipes.
你想
You wanna...
不  我不知道
No, I don't... I don't know, I...
得了吧  莱瑞
Oh, come on, Larry.
你上一次射在真正的阴道里
How long has it been since you came in a real live vagina
而不是自己手上  已经有多久了
and not in your hand? Huh?
-好吧  -来吧  我们上楼
- Okay. - Come on, let's go upstairs.
不  我要去下卫生间
No, I need to... I'm gonna use the bathroom.
我想你不应该喝酒  亲爱的
I don't think you're supposed to be drinking, honey.
你知道"应该"是什么意思吗
What's "Supposed to," Anyway, you know?
是谁定的这些规矩
Who makes those rules?
我相信你这个情况下
I believe it's the Federal
规矩是联邦惩教局定的
Department of Corrections in this case.
去他们的
Fuck 'em.
任何人都不愿看你因为在休假期间
The last thing anyone needs is you getting your sentence extended
违反一些愚蠢的规定而使刑期延长
for some silly furlough violation.
真的吗  爸爸
Really, Dad?
是其他人不愿看到
Is that the last thing that anyone needs,
还是你自己不愿看到
or is that the last thing that you need,
因为你拒绝去监狱探访自己唯一的女儿
because you refuse to come visit your only daughter in prison
你不希望因为这事让自己的良心
and you'd rather not have that weighing on your conscience
受到更多谴责  是吗
for any longer than it has to?
帕波  我们现在能别说这些吗
Piper, can we not do this now, please?
我母亲过世了
My mother has died.
好吧  对不起
Fine. Sorry.
塞莱斯特非常以你为傲
Celeste was so proud of you.
从你出生的那刻起
From the moment you were born.
现在很难想象这是真的
It's hard to imagine that's true anymore.
真的  我甚至觉得因为我生了你  她更喜欢我了
It was. I even think she liked me more for having fathered you.
亲爱的  对不起
I'm sorry, honey.
我只是不能看到你那个样子
I just can't see you like that.
哪个样子
Like what?
你是我的宝贝女儿
You're my little girl.
监狱里的那个女人  不是真正的你
That woman in there, that's not who you are.
那就是我自己
That's exactly who I am.
莱瑞
Larry?
我在里面
I'm in here, hello?
停停  帕波
Hey, hey, hey! Pipes...
好了  帕波  别在这儿
Okay. Piper, not here. What if...
天呐  帕波  你确定吗
Piper. Jesus, Piper. Oh, God, are you sure about this?
门锁了吗  门有没有锁上
Is the door locked? Is the door locked? Is the door locked?
该死  我的天
Shit. Oh, my God.
干我
Fuck me.
好吧  把你腿抬高
Okay. Okay, just move your leg over.
好  像这样吗
Okay. Like that?
-你好了吗  -是的
- Are you okay? - Yeah.
好
Okay.
-该死  -怎么了
- Shit. - What? Oh.
-该死  -没关系  我来帮你
- Fuck. - It's okay. Let me help.
抱歉  我一直想着你爸突然闯进来
I'm sorry. I can't stop thinking about your dad walking in.
别  别  天呐  帕波  你不用
No! No! Oh, Jesus, Piper, you don't have to...
该死  拜托  这太奇怪了
Oh, fuck. Come on, this is weird.
我们还在服丧
We're mourning. We're...
我们那么久没做了  我们甚至不在一起
Ah... We haven't done this in so long. We're not even together.
莱瑞  闭嘴
Larry. Shut up.
该死  我睡了别人
Fuck, I slept with someone.
-真的吗  -对不起
- Really? - I'm sorry.
你在我帮你的软鸡巴口时决定跟我说这个
You decide to tell me that with your flaccid dick in my mouth?
嘘  半硬了
Ssh! It was a semi.
现在别在我面前维护你的鸡鸡
Do not defend your boner to me right now.
抱歉  我知道这件事
I'm sorry. I know this is...
你很难接受
tough for you.
你有没有什么想问我的或者
Is there anything you wanna ask me or...
不  上帝  我没有
No. God, no.
可能吧  是我认识的人吗
Maybe. Is it someone that I know?
是的
Yes.
够了  别的我不想知道
That's it. I don't wanna know anything else.
求你别跟我说其他的
Please don't tell me anything else.
没错  能在脑子里回想的感觉更糟
Yeah, well, it's much worse when you can imagine it in your own head.
相信我
Trust me.
这下真的结束了  对吗
This is really over, isn't it?
我也不想变成这样
I don't... I don't want it to be.
是的  你想
Yes, you do.
但真的说出来  感觉很糟糕
But it feels so shitty actually saying it.
我知道
I know.
该死  我会想你的
Fuck, I'm gonna miss you.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
你明天不用来我奶奶的葬礼
You don't have to come to my grandmother's funeral tomorrow.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank God.
是啊
Yeah.
你起早干活又不会有小红花拿
You ain't gonna get a gold star for showin' up early.
那个警卫  真是个非常可怕的男人
That guard, that awful, awful man.
哪一个
Which one?
新来的那个警卫
That new guard.
坏版的伯特・雷诺兹  但更流氓
D-list Burt Reynolds but more rapey.
伯特・雷诺兹  著名演员
曾获金球奖最佳男配角奖
黄胡
Pornstache.
没错  他让我加班干活
Yeah. He gave me extra work duty.
他因为我有信念而惩罚我
He's punishing me for believing in something.
这里的人们可不喜欢信仰
Well, people don't like conviction around here. Okay?
这是不行的  先生
No, sir.
我会给他们好好瞧瞧的
Well, I'm gonna show them.
很快就没人会吃东西了  他们会看到的
Soon, no one will be eating, and then they'll see.
我们为什么不吃东西
Why ain't we eating?
为了抗议这里的条件
In protest of the conditions in here.
那真是太傻逼了
Well, that's just super stupid.
真弱智  又下贱又残忍又傻逼
And dumb. And mean and cruel and stupid.
没错  我说了傻逼两次
And, yeah, I said "Stupid" Twice,
就是为了强调这事有多傻逼
only to emphasize how stupid that is.
别去说花木兰了
Hey, leave Mulan alone.
其实我叫布鲁克  布鲁克・苏苏
It's Brook, actually. Soso.
你知道吗  你是对的  苏苏
You know what? You're right, Soso.
看看这地方  虽然我们是罪犯
You know, look around this place. We're criminals,
但那并不意味着我们
but that don't mean we don't
不应该受到正常人一样的待遇
deserve to be treated like normal people.
一点也没错
Exactly.
你什么时候开始关心监狱条件了  琳恩
Since when do you care about the conditions, Leanne?
一直以来都关心
Since always.
没人喜欢像动物一样活着
Nobody likes to live like an animal.
那么你想加入我吗
So, you wanna join me?
这取决于今天的午餐供应什么
It depends on what they're serving for lunch today,
但我会考虑的
but I'll think on it.
好的  如果你想知道的话
Okay. You know, I could tell you more about
我可以多跟你讲讲以前的有效监狱绝食
the efficacy of prison hunger strikes historically, if you want.
那听起来真的很有趣
That sounds real interesting.
太棒了  星际宝贝
Great. Lilo and Stitch
星际宝贝  迪斯尼公司动画片
想让自己挨饿来拯救世界  真的是
starving themselves to save the world. This is...
她是莉萝  对吧
She's Lilo, isn't she?
莉萝  星际宝贝中的女主角
那你在说我是史迪奇了
So, you're saying that I'm Stitch,
史迪奇  星际宝贝中的怪兽主角
你这个没有朋友的怪物
you friendless freak?
没人喜欢你
No one likes you.
你们迷路了吗  我们早饭还没做好呢
Aw, are you guys lost? We ain't ready for breakfast yet.
但今天我们有奶油麦片粥  适合老人家的
But today, we have cream of wheat. Yay. Old-people food.
你妈妈没有教你要尊老吗
Didn't your mother teach you manners?
你们这些老家伙为什么脾气总那么暴躁
Why you old people always gotta be so cranky all the time?
就是  你们是来教我们狗屁德育课的吗
Yeah, you here to teach us a morality lesson and shit?
我们是来拿走属于红妈的东西
We're here to collect what belongs to Red.
我们什么也不知道
Well, we don't know nothing about that, so...
你真可爱啊
Aren't you cute?
你是不是被卷入了你男友的毒品交易
Did you get caught up in your boyfriend's drug game?
你想知道我犯了什么事吗
You wanna know what I did?
我用切肉刀割了我老公的鸡巴
Cut my husband's dick off with a butcher knife,
用的那把刀甚至都不锋利
and it wasn't even sharp.
我仍然能够梦到那个画面
I still dream about it,
好多血  血滴到我拳头上的样子
all the blood, the way it flopped around in my fist.
那可是我的人生杰作
Hmm. Best thing I ever did.
年纪大了被人低估真是太让人失望了
It's so disappointing being underestimated as you age.
我不知道发生了什么事
I don't know what happened.
没人会告诉新来的人
Nobody tells the new girl.
前一天她还在掌管一切  当着老大
One day, she was running things, large and in charge.
后一天就消失不见了  再见朗达
And the next, poof, gone. So long, Rhonda.
她身上肯定出了什么大事
Something major must've happened for her
才被关押到重刑监狱  对吧
to be sent down to max, no?
是啊  谁知道这里的规矩是怎么样的
Yeah, well, who knows how stuff works around here?
你听说昨晚安妮塔心脏病发作的事了吗
You hear Anita had a heart attack last night?
和我们住一起的那个意大利人吗
The guido who rooms with us?
可能她动脉里的肉酱太多了
Probably too much ragù in her arteries.
说到这事
Speaking of...
把你手放进去
Put your hand in.
天呐  那太不卫生了
Oh, God. That's unsanitary.
只管做就是了
Just do it.
拉出来
Pull.
我勒个去
Holy shit.
对白人女孩来说还算不错吧
Not too bad for a white girl, hmm?
真的很不错  你已经开始卖了吗
Not too bad at all. You selling already?
一点点  四处卖卖  试试深浅
A little. Here and there. Testing the waters.
我可不想冲昏头脑办坏事
I don't wanna get in over my head.
几个月之后你就会成为这里的老大了
Shit, you gonna be running things around here in a few months.
到时候见分晓  我要稳扎稳打
We'll see. Slow and steady.
但我谢谢你的建议
But I do thank you for your advice.
维  抱歉打扰你
Hey, Vee, I'm sorry to bother you,
那个没眉毛的女人
but the one without the eyebrows,
她没拿到钱
she ain't got her money.
根据你的吩咐  我想你是要亲自处理
Figured you'd wanna deal yourself like you told us.
我马上去
I'll be right there.
我得走了  我们等一会儿再聊
I better get going. We can talk more later.
我真是大开眼界  红妈
I'm impressed, Red.
红妈帮我对付了门德斯
Red helped me with Mendez.
整个监狱都知道了吗
Does the entire prison know?
没别人了  宝贝  我保证  你要放松
That's it. I promise. Babe, you need to relax.
他回来了你怎么还能假装一切都很好
How can you act like everything is fine when he's back here?
他会毁掉我们的生活
He could ruin our lives.
他会毁了我的生活
He could... He could ruin my life.
一切都会好的  红妈在我们这边
Everything's gonna be fine. Red's on our side.
门德斯甚至都没试着跟我谈话
And Mendez doesn't even try to talk to me.
很好  我肯定他们会
Good, I mean, I'm sure they probably...
我肯定他们会告诉他尽可能远离你
I'm sure they probably told him to stay as far away as possible.
只是感到有一点奇怪
Just feels a little weird since,
毕竟他喜欢我
you know, he's in love with me or whatever.
至少也该试着跟我打个招呼
You would think that he'd try to say hi.
好了  我
Okay, you know, I...
我要去告诉卡普托  门德斯是孩子的爸爸
I'm gonna tell Caputo that Mendez is the father.
但你那是撒谎
But that's a lie.
他没有和你做过爱吗
But didn't he have sex with you?
-做过  -好了  那他就是罪犯
- Yeah. - Okay, so he's a criminal,
他应该被关进监狱
he deserves to go to prison.
但你也和我做过  不管怎么说以前做过
But you have sex with me. Used to, anyways.
那不一样  我是爱你的
That's different. I... I love you.
他也一样
So does he.
你现在是在为他辩护吗
Are you actually defending him right now?
我只是无法相信
I just can't believe that
你要把一个无罪之人送进监狱
you would send an innocent man to prison.
抱歉  你在说什么  整个
I'm sorry, what? The whole...
整个计划就是把他送进监狱
The whole plan was to send him to prison.
所以你才会和他做爱  难道不是吗
I mean, that's why you fucked him in the first place, was it not?
只不过这事没成功
It's just... It just didn't work.
我不知道我在做什么  她们把我说服了
I don't know what I was doing. They talked me into it.
你知道我妈有时多吓人
You know how scary my mom can be.
但我花了点时间来反省  他是无辜的
But I've had time to reflect, and he's innocent.
拜托  达娅
Oh, come on, Daya, you know
你知道他应该被关进监狱
he deserves to go to prison for something.
生活就是这样的
This is... This is just how life works.
我需要时间考虑
Well, I need time to think.
在没和我商量过之前  你不许做别的事
Don't you go doing nothing without talking to me.
听到了吗
You hear me?
你是要我打完飞机还是怎么样
Now, you want me to finish or what?
好的
Yes.
求你了  特别红灯
Red light special, please.
你们这些人就像"不要吸毒"的三维广告
Man, you people are like a 3D "Don't do drugs" Ad.
暗号不对吗
Ain't that the code?
该死  你要那么多吗
Damn, you want that many?
它不是就是这个价钱吗
Isn't that what it costs?
你在说什么
What are you talkin' about?
那东西
The stuff.
你可以说香烟这个词
You can say, "Cigarette."
什么  不是  我要特别的东西
What? No. The special stuff.
我知道黑妞们在卖
I know the black girls are selling it.
你是说我们看起来都一样吗
You saying we all look alike?
拜托  我的整张脸都很痛
Come on, my face is all achy.
我想暂时失去知觉
I need to not feel it for a while.
那就去小卖部买点阿司匹林  滚出去
Then go buy some aspirin from commissary. Get out of here.
这些我就留下了  因为你浪费了我的时间
And I'm keeping these for my time.
快走
Go.
有一个圣诞节  我第一次被允许
This one Christmas, I was allowed to help Grandmother
帮奶奶制作她非常著名的糖果曲奇
make her really famous sugar cookies for the very first time.
我想你们大多数这些年来
I think most of you have probably
都收到过她做的一罐饼干
received a tin of her cookies over the years.
如果没收到  说明奶奶不喜欢你们
If you didn't, Grandmother didn't like you.
我只是随便说说
I'm just sayin'.
不管怎样  5分钟不到我就陷入了麻烦
Anyway, it took less than five minutes for me to mess up,
我在生面团里倒了太多小苏打
and I poured too much baking soda into the dough
我马上哭了起来
and I immediately started crying.
我以为我彻底毁了圣诞节
I thought I had completely ruined Christmas.
但奶奶并没有吼我
But instead of yelling at me,
她告诉我一切都会没事的
Grandmother told me that they were gonna be fine,
她当时说的更好听
and she said better, even. And then...
她对我说  帕波  生活就是由错误组成的
And then she said to me, "Piper, life is made in the mistakes."
现在回想起来  她肯定在我走后重新做了
In retrospect, I'm sure she remade them after I left, you know?
抱歉
I'm sorry.
没事的  没事的
It's okay. It's okay.
这女人叫塞莱斯特  是吧
I mean, the woman's name was Celeste, for God's sake.
抱歉  抱歉  神父
Uh, sorry. Sorry. Sorry, Father.
我不知道在场的各位
Um, I don't know if any of you
是否听过这些东西的演奏
have ever heard one of those things played before.
我是说钢片琴
A celeste, I mean,
celeste亦有钢片琴之意
但那有种神奇而飘渺的感觉
but it is this magical, ethereal experience.
所有这些钢板发出的声响听起来就像
All these steel plates that ting and sound like,
我说不清楚  就像
I don't know, like,
就像是大海突然开始奏乐
if an ocean were to suddenly make music.
其实那并不太像奶奶
Um... That's... That's not really like Grandmother,
但她非常特别
but she was, she was special.
即使你知道自己只是茫茫人海之中
She... She made you feel like
毫不起眼的小人物
there was something important about you
她也会让你感到
even when you knew you were nothing
自己拥有不平凡之处
but a polyp in the sea of human mundanity.
说了很多关于大海的比喻
Lot of ocean imagery here.
但听着  重点是奶奶是个了不起的女人
But look, the point is that Grandmother was a wonderful woman.
那是我要说的重点
That's the point I'm trying to make.
她应该得到纪念
And she should be celebrated.
我的妹妹帕波在这里  真的非常不可思议
And my sister, Piper, is here, and that is truly incredible
因为严格地说她受到联邦政府的监护
because she is technically a ward of the federal government.
或是刚从非洲回来的  凯西阿姨
Or... just returned from Africa, Aunt Kathy.
不管怎样  今天是感恩生命的一天
Um... Either way, today is a day to celebrate life.
今天是值得庆祝的一天
Today is a day to celebrate today.
所以
And that is why...
我想不出更合适的时间来做这事
that is why I can't think of a better time to do this.
来吧  来吧  我可爱的灰树花
Come on. Come on, my little hen of the woods.
朋友们  家人们
Friends, family...
-快做些什么  -恋人们
- Do something. - ... lovers,
我记不住名字的年长亲戚们
older family friends that I can never remember the names of,
内莉和我准备结婚
Neri and I are getting married...
就在此刻
right now...
在座的各位都将成为我们的见证人
with all of you as our witnesses.
我们的朋友都来了  帕波也休假了
Our friends are here, Piper's on furlough,
我们的好友山姆  上周为我们受戒
our buddy, Sam, got ordained last week just for us.
谢谢你  山姆
Thank you, Sam.
内莉的家人也来了
Neri's family is here.
后面的帕姆和乔
Pam and Joe in the back.
伙计们  你们太可爱了  真棒
Hi, guys. You're so cute. You are awesome.
感谢你们的到来  爱你们
Thank you for coming. Love you. And...
我相信塞莱斯特
I think that Celeste...
会对我们免费蹭花和食物感到开心的
would be pleased with our judicious use of the free flowers and food,
或许会有一点点不满
if not a tiny bit judgmental.
我觉得她会称赞我们的精神  对吧
And I think that she would admire our spirit, right?
帕波
Pipes.
我们去大快朵颐吧
We're gonna eat the world.
抱歉了  老妈
Sorry, Mom.
你在干什么啊
Yo, what the hell are you doin'?
我要和你谈谈  我觉得维在贩卖毒品
I need to talk to you. I think Vee's bringin' in drugs.
珀比  每天重复同样的对话
P, ain't you bored of
你难道不觉得无聊吗
havin' the same damn conversation every day?
反正我觉得会无聊
Shit, I know I am.
你给我听着  好吗  有一个冰妹
Yo, just listen, all right? One of them meth heads...
停  你何不听话别再说三道四了
No! Why don't you listen and stop running your mouth?
谁在乎她在做什么  那是她的事
Who cares what she's doing? That's her business.
她一直对我很好
She's been real good to me,
我可不想背弃她
and I am not about to turn away from that.
维是我的家人
Vee is my family.
我以为我才是你的家人
Thought I was your family.
你俩都是我的家人
You both are my family, yo, like...
如果我们俩
What if we was...
如果我们俩同时掉进海里
What if we was drownin' in the middle of the ocean,
你只能救我们之中的一个
and you could only save one of us?
为什么我不能把你们都救了
Why can't I save both of you?
我不知道  因为你不能
I don't know. Because you can't.
因为船上没有足够位置
'Cause there's not enough room in the boat.
难道是全世界最小的船吗
It's, like, the world's tiniest boat or some shit?
没错  好吧  就是这样
Yes, okay? Yes.
就像是给小孩坐的小木筏  好吧
It's like a little raft for kiddies and shit, all right?
-你能回答我的问题吗  -听好了  珀比
- Can you just play the game with me? - Listen up, pussy.
我爱你  但我受够了
I love you, but I am done
我不想再翻来覆去听你说这屁事
as a burnt burger talkin' about this shit.
别再跟我或跟别人说维的事
No more talkin' about Vee to me or to anyone.
珀比  那女人不是闹着玩的
And, P, that woman don't play around.
别妨碍她
Don't get in her way.
也别妨碍我  听到了吗
Or mine. You hear?
听到了
Yeah.
怎么了  德盖特
What happened, Doggett?
你知道我有时候会发疯
You know I get mad sometimes.
我知道我一直是个恶霸  我知道
I know I've been a bully. I know.
但是我真的很想重新开始
But I was really trying to turn a new leaf.
求你了
Please...
别送我去关禁闭  求你了  海利先生
Please don't send me down to SHU, Mr. Healy, please.
那里真的很可怕
It is truly awful down there.
德盖特  你是不是总是容易生气
Doggett, have you always been quick to anger?
你是什么意思
What you mean?
是不是愤怒的那个你就在外表之下
I mean, does it sit right below the surface?
在不经意间就突然爆发连自己都会大吃一惊
Does it bubble up and surprise you when you're not expecting it?
你这里是不是像打鼓一样
Do you have a pounding right here?
感觉就像血管要爆裂一样
Like, feels like a vein's gonna explode?
是的
Yeah.
你是灵媒吗
Are you a psychic or something?
不是
No.
那你怎么此刻像在我脑袋里一样
How are you in my head, then, right now?
因为我自己也暴躁易怒
Because I've had anger issues of my own...
我发现换个角度看问题
and what I've found is that a change of perspective
能让一切变得不同
can make all the difference.
你的意思是不是向左看而不是向右看
Do you mean, like, looking left rather than right kind of thing?
正是这样
Exactly like that.
我不把你送去关禁闭
Instead of me sending you down to SHU,
我要你每周来见我一次
I want you to come and visit me once a week.
我们做什么
What would we do?
说话
Talk.
我们要谈什么
What will we talk about?
我可以为你的一些问题提供建议
I could counsel you through some of these issues.
好的  谢谢
Yes, thank you. Yes.
你真的是太好了  海利先生
That's so awfully nice of you, Mr. Healy.
我是个好人  那是事实
I'm a nice guy. That's the truth.
或许她们迟到了
Maybe they're runnin' late.
这里是监狱  她们现在不会迷路的
Nah, it's a prison. They didn't get lost in the moment.
爱拿什么拿什么
take whatever.
不是  我是说为什么你老为难我
No, I mean, Jesus, why you fucking breaking my balls?
伙计  说服她们可要
Man, this took way more convincing than
比两盒燕麦馅饼的价钱高得多
two boxes of oatmeal pies are worth.
请坐  我想我们可以享受一顿家庭聚餐
Please, sit. I thought we could enjoy a family meal together.
是你做的吗
You made this?
你没有厨房还怎么做这些东西
How the fuck you do this without a kitchen?
我是个优秀的即兴厨师
I'm a good improviser.
况且我还有这些女恶霸的帮助
And I had some help from the baddest bitches around.
闻起来棒极了  红妈
It smells wonderful, Red.
并不代表好吃
Doesn't mean it tastes good.
爸爸今晚要烂醉如泥了
Ooh! Daddy's getting blotto tonight, huh?
感谢你能来  我知道你不一定要来的
Thank you for coming. I know you didn't have to.
红妈  你得让我们知道你的秘诀
Hey, Red. Got to let us in on the secret.
这太疯狂了
I mean, this shit is crazy.
你们是我的家人
You're my family.
在座的各位对我来说都很重要
All of you are very important to me.
过去几个月以来
And I... let a lot of things
我让很多事情影响了我们之间的关系
get in the way of that these past few months.
我真的
I truly...
老家伙们  给我来点那个吃的好吗
Golden oldies. How about I get some of that slop down here, huh?
说真的  给我上菜吧
Seriously. Food me.
我正在给大家讲话呢
I'm trying to have a moment.
闭嘴吃你的东西吧
Now shut up and eat.
谢谢
Thank you.
正如我所说的
As I was saying,
我意识到我从未说这句最重要的话
I realize I never said the most important thing...
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
红妈  我们没有你也也过得还好
You know, Red, we've done okay without you.
我知道  但我希望你过得更好
I know you have, but I want you to do better than okay.
没错  但或许我们并不怀念某些部分
Yeah, but maybe there are some parts that we didn't miss so much.
比如受你摆布
Like being pushed around.
或是被烧伤
Or burned.
吉纳  我不知道是否能用言语表达
Gina, I don't know that I'll ever have the words
我对你的遭遇有多么后悔
to express the regret I feel for what happened to you.
我犯了错
I made a mistake.
我希望你接受我的道歉
I hope you accept my apology.
好的
Okay.
我愿意让我们之间变得更加民主
I'm willing to make this more of a democracy,
如果这是大家所希望的
if that's what you all want.
我只是希望我的家人能回到我的身边
I just want my family back.
过来抱抱  红妈
Oh, get over here, Red.
诺尔玛  我亲爱的诺尔玛
Norma. My dear Norma,
这么多年来你一直在我身边
you've been by my side for many years.
你站在我身边  听我的指挥
You stood beside me, listened to me,
帮我拔去肩膀后面奇怪胎记上的胎毛
plucked the hair out of that weird mole on the back of my arm.
你是我最好的朋友  我很想你
You're my best friend, and I miss you so much.
谢谢你能再给我一次机会
Thank you for giving me another chance.
那我呢
What about me?
你没有什么特别的话要跟我说吗
Don't you have a special dedication for me?
大波  谢谢你一直让我看着不顺眼
Boo, thank you, for always being a pain in my ass.
从现在开始  让我们团结一致
Let's stick together from now on, huh?
你想要什么
What do you want?
听说你在这里
Hear you have a pretty good system
搞了个不错的小生意
worked out for yourself in here.
诺尔玛  给这位好女士拿张表格
Norma... get the nice young woman a form.
写下你要的东西  我会尽力的
Write down what you want, and I'll do my best.
虽然我们最近订单有点超负荷
We're a little overwhelmed with orders lately, though.
我不是来这下订单的  我是来买你公司的
I ain't here to place no orders. Here to buy the company.
抱歉  概不出售
It's not for sale, sorry.
你都不想听下报价吗
You don't even wanna hear the offer?
你可以试试看
Try me.
你可以住在最低安全级别的舒适区域内
You get to stay in cozy minimum security.
并且我们也不会打断你的肋骨
Oh, and we don't break your ribs.
亲爱的  你选择挑起了
You, my dear, have chosen
一场无法赢得的战争
the one fight in here that can't be won.
跑去告诉你老妈
Go run to your mommy,
跟她说红妈要跟她谈谈
tell her Red needs to talk to her,
然后我们大人们自然会讨论的
then the adults will discuss this.
你知道那是个极其愚蠢的决定  对吧
You know that's a real stupid move, right?
我很高兴帮你邀请她来
I mean, I'm happy to go get her for you.
反正今天已经有够无聊了
Today has been kind of boring, anyhow.
去吧  去吧  快去
Go. Go, go, go.
不好意思  或许我真的是个白痴
I'm sorry. Maybe I'm just an idiot.
因为我想了很久也没想明白
'Cause I'm having a hard motherfucking time understanding
三个老女人是怎么来这里偷了我们的东西
how three little old ladies come in here and stole from us.
她们真的很吓人
They was really scary.
就是  她们其中有个人看着像迪斯尼的女巫
Yeah, and one of 'em looked like a Disney witch.
你知道吗  快从我面前滚蛋
You know what? Go! Get... Get out of my face.
红妈向你表示道歉
Red sends her apologies.
我讨厌这个厨房
I hate this kitchen.
这他妈是什么
What the fuck is this? Huh?
这是什么
What is this?
你以为自己能在这里偷偷抽这东西吗
You think you can just get away with this shit in here?
你以为我会视而不见吗
You think I'm gonna turn a blind eye?
以为我是个娘们吗
Think I'm a pussy?
是时候要像以前一样搜查了  女士们
It's time for a good old-fashioned search, ladies.
这是什么
Oh, what is this?
非法违禁品吗
Illegal contraband?
囚犯  你那么安静  现在没话说了吗
You're awfully quiet, inmate. Got nothing to say now?
你害怕了吗  你他妈就应该害怕
You scared? 'Cause you fucking should be!
这里归我管理  我是老大
I'm in control! I'm in charge!
-我操  -停停停  伙计
- Fuckin'... - Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Buddy!
我们要整死你们  把你们全部整死
We are gonna fucking crack down on you! On all of you!
你会害自己被炒的  伙计
Hey! You're gonna get yourself fired, pal.
没事了  行了
It's okay. Come on.
你还好吗  来吧  我们走
You all right? Come on. Let's get you out of here.
女士们  都没事了
Everything's okay, ladies.
把这里整理干净  好吧
Just clean this shit up, all right?
抱歉打扰你们了  走吧
Sorry for the fuss. Come on.
你没事了  伙计  走吧
You're all right, buddy. Come on.
现在女士们先生们
And now, ladies and gentlemen,
新娘和新郎第一次闪亮登场
for the very first time, the bride and the groom.
真的很高兴你能来  帕波
It's so wonderful that you could be here, Piper.
你还好吗
How are you doing?
挺好  我很好
Fine. I'm fine.
如果朱莉像你这个样子的话
We would be so heartbroken for our Julie
我们会很伤心的
if she were in your position.
你知道吗  我们刚还在说
You know what, we were just talking earlier
你曾经是个多么棒的孩子
about what a wonderful kid you were.
总是在报纸上看到你  一直很成功
Always in the newspaper for something and always achieving.
亲爱的  我们只想告诉你
We just want you to know, dear,
我们觉得你还是原来那个你
we still see you as that person.
我相信你很渴望做回自己
I'm sure you're anxious to return to your old self.
事实上  我不渴望
I'm not, actually.
出租
好了
Well, now.
我等的黑美人终于来了
There's the black beauty I've been waitin' for.
我能帮你吗
Can I help you?
妹子  我觉得应该反过来说才是
I think that's the other way around, sistah.
老天啊  难道我在这里
Jesus. Can't even brush your teeth around here
都不能安安静静刷个牙吗
without getting into something.
你到底要干什么
What do you want, man?
找到另一个走私路子对你而言值多少
How much would it be worth to you to find another route in?
取决于这个路子到哪的
Depends on where the route goes.
你懂得  除非我知道能得到什么
Oh, now, you know I can't give you information
否则我不能把信息告诉你
unless I know what I'm getting for it.
我应该对这个有兴趣吗
And I'm supposed to be interested in that?
我知道红妈是怎么把违禁品运进来的
I know how Red's importing contraband.
有兴趣吗
Interested in that?
而且我还知道警卫们快发现你们了
'Cause I also know that the guards are hot on your trail.
所以你需要一个新的掩护  对吧
So you're gonna need a new cover, right?
我要烟草收益的2成
I want 20% of tobacco intake.
你真是个自以为是的拉拉  不是吗
You are a smug little dyke, aren't you?
不不不  我是又壮又聪明的拉拉
Oh, no, no, no, no, no. I am a big, smart dyke.
是的  夫人
Yes, ma'am.
1成
10%.
成交
Got yourself a deal.
你是不是把你的野狗栓回去了
Did you get your pack of wild dogs under control?
她们一直很听话
They're always obedient.
那就好  我不想在这里再见到她们
Good. Then I'll look forward to never seeing them in here again.
红妈  你以为是谁下的命令
Who do you think gave the order, Red?
你是我的朋友
You're my friend.
我不记得我们有交换过友谊手链
I don't remember us exchanging woven bracelets.
你不能夺走我的生意  这是我创立的
You're not taking over my business. I started it.
拜托  难道我们不能分享吗
Come on. Can't we share?
当初难道不是我给你出的主意吗
Didn't I give you the idea in the first place?
现在一下子就成了你的了吗
Now all of a sudden, it's yours?
你对朗达做了什么
What did you do to Rhonda?
以后就这样好了
Here's what's gonna happen.
你继续接受订单并出货
You're gonna keep taking orders and filling them.
我的人负责配送和收钱
My girls will be distributing the goods and collecting the payments.
我会告诉海利的
I'll tell Healy.
红妈
Oh, Red.
你那么做的话
You do that,
我会保证你的下场就和朗达一样
and I will make sure that you end up exactly like Rhonda.
你休想把我的生意夺走
You are not taking this from me.
你犯的第一个错误就是没有后援
Your first mistake is not having backup.
动手
Go ahead.
我有个礼物要给你
Hey, I got a gift for you.
乱说  我生日都没到
Shit, it's not even my birthday.
第一次免费  如果还要的话就跟我说
First one's free. Let me know if you want more.
当我说证明给我看的时候
When I said prove it,
我意思是像泰勒教练那样
I meant it in a Coach Taylor kind of way.
泰勒教练  《胜利之光》中的经典角色
而不是恐吓囚犯  让自己停职
Not a "Terrify all the inmates, get yourself suspended" Way.
抱歉  先生  我也不知道自己是怎么了
Sorry, sir. I don't know what... I don't know what got into me.
本尼特  现在麻烦事够多了
I don't have time for any more headaches
我没时间再处理更多的头痛事了
on top of everything else right now, Bennett.
我知道  只是记过配额指标
I understand. I'm just... just under a lot of stress
以及一些私事  让我感到很有压力
with the shot quota and some, uh... some personal stuff.
好吧  你的私事
Yes, and your personal crap
应该和你的小玩具一起放在家里
belongs at home next to your tchotchkes.
但问题就在这儿  先生
Well, that's the thing, sir,
我并不能把那件事放在家中
I... can't exactly leave this stuff at home.
你想跟我说什么
What are you trying to tell me?
迪亚茨怀孕了  达娅娜
Diaz is pregnant. Dayanara.
什么
What?
肯定是门德斯的
Must've been Mendez.